[MUSIC]
[음악]
Okay, so far we've assumed that the only feature relevant to the value of my house,
지금까지 저의 집 가치에 관련된 특징은
is the square feet of the house.
평수만 있다고 가정했습니다
But I dig into the data set a little bit more, and
데이터 세트를 조금만 뒤져서
I look at a house that's supposed to be very similar to mine.
저의 집과 비슷하다고 여겨지는 집을
It's a house that has very similar square footage.
살펴보면 비슷한 평수를 갖고 있습니다
And so, this house is definitely making an influence on what the predictions are for
그러니 이 집은 저의 집 가치 예측에
my house.
분명히 영향을 끼치고 있습니다
But I look at it and I say, and I look at the specific listing, and
하지만 매물 정보를 잘 살펴보면
it shows that that house only had one bathroom.
이 집에는 화장실이 하나밖에 없습니다
It's actually quite a big house, only one bathroom.
꽤 큰 집이지만 화장실이 하나입니다
And I say that's really, really not comparable to my house,
그러면 화장실이 세 개인 저의 집과는
which has three bathrooms.
직접 비교하기 힘들죠
So that the value of that house, that house sales price
이 집의 가치, 판매 가격은 저의 집
really shouldn't be indicative of what my house sales price should be.
판매 가격을 좌우하는 지표가 되어선 안 됩니다
So instead what we can think about doing is adding more features.
이 부분을 고려해 특징을 더 추가합니다
So instead of just looking at the relationship between square feet and
평수와 가격 사이의 관련성만을 보기보다는
price, we can add number of bathrooms.
화장실 개수 또한 살펴봅니다
And now for
이제
each one of the listings that I looked at before, I'm gonna have to go through and
매물 정보를 살펴볼 때 평수뿐만 아니라
record how many square feet that house had, and the number of bathrooms.
화장실 개수도 같이 기록합니다
And I'm gonna plot each of these points in the 3D space.
그리고 이 점들을 3차원 공간에 그립니다
Okay? So it's this hyper cube of square
평수 대 화장실 개수 대 가격이
feet versus bathrooms versus price.
직육면체로 그려집니다
And now instead of fitting a line to the data, if I'm thinking about just a very
간단한 모델을 구할 때처럼
simple model, I can think about fitting a hyper plane.
데이터에 선을 그어서 맞추는 게 아니라 초평면으로 맞춥니다
Okay, so it's just a slice through the space.
공간을 분할하는 거죠
We're here.
이렇게
This is the equation of the hyper plane, and this is the equation of this plane.
초평면 공식이고 이 평면의 공식이 됩니다
So we have w0, which is our intercept, just where this plane lives up and
절편 w0이 있는데 이 평면이 y축 어디에
down on the y-axis.
위치해 있는냐를 나타냅니다
And we have w1 times the number of square feet, and
w1 곱하기 평수와
w2 times the number of bathrooms.
w2 곱하기 화장실 개수가 있습니다
But a question is where do we stop?
그런데 어디까지 해야 할까요?
Do we just want to include the number of bathrooms as our additional feature?
화장실 개수만 특징으로 추가하면 될까요?
There are lots of things we could think about including.
포함시키고자 한다면 여러 개를 떠올릴 수 있습니다
We could think about in addition to our square feet, number of bathrooms,
평수와 화장실 개수에 더해서
there's the number of bedrooms, the lot size, how old the house is, and
침실 개수, 대지면적, 주택연령 등
the list goes on and on.
특징 세트가 있다고 하죠
In terms of different properties of the house that could be influential in
주택의 여러 특성을
assessing it's value.
고려할 수 있습니다
But we're gonna actually hold off on this question of looking at which features
어떤 특징이 중요한지에 대해선
are important for this regression task, until we get to the regression course.
회귀 강의까지 우선 제쳐 놓겠습니다
So go to the regression course to learn more about this topic.
회귀 강의에서 이 주제에 대해 더 자세히 배우게 될 것입니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]